William Beverley Pettit Correspondence WLU.Coll.0199
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
William Beverley Pettit Correspondence
Inclusive 1850-1918
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
WLU.Coll.0199
.4 Linear Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of J. Nathaniel Hamrick.
Biographical Note
William B. Pettit, an attorney from Fluvanna, Va., was Commonwealth's Attorney for the district, 1864-1872; President of the Virginia Bar Association, 1898; and member of the State Constitutional Convention, 1901-1902.
Scope and Contents
This is a collection of correspondence between William B. Pettit and his wife Arabella ('Bell') with scattered letters from other friends and relatives. The letters that date from 1850 to March 1862 include correspondence between husband and wife while Pettit was away on business. The war letters begin in March 1862 and end with Pettit's last war letter to his wife on March 3, 1864. After that date there are letters from Pembroke, the Pettit's son, while he attended school at Ashland, Va. The turn of the century correspondence concerns Confederate Veterans' activities and post-war business correspondence. Also included are newspaper clippings, one photograph, and the obituary of William B. Pettit (1905). The collection also includes Pettit's Civil War manuscript diary, 1862-1864, and account book. These two books are bound together.
Personal narratives -- Confederate; Virginia; Diaries; Soliders; Correspondence; Virginia -- Fluvanna County; Biography; Pettit, William Beverley; Pettit, Arabella Speairs; Pettit, Pembroke; Confederate States of America. Army. Virginia Artillery. Fluvanna Artillery
- Control Folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1850-1861 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1862-03-1862-06 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1862-07-1862-12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1863-01-1863-04 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1863-05-1863-08 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1863-09-1863-12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1864-01-1864-04 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1864-05-1864-06 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1864-07-1864-09 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1864-10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1864-11-1864-12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1865-1873 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- United Confederate Veterans Notices and Correspondence, 1896-1918 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence Fragments and Miscellaneous Items (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Diary and Account Book, 1862-04-1864-04 (Box 1, Folder 16)